Guide to the Papers of the Williams Family 1739-1842 (Bulk 1747-1770) MS 698
@ 2011 New-York Historical Society
- Series IX. Personal Items and Notes (1693-1741, undated)
  Among the items in this series are Thomas Williams' 1741 Yale diploma (Box 2, Folder 1) and a notebook of religious questions, answers and arguments belonging to William Williams (Box 2, Folder 11). Several lists of children's birth dates are included in Box 2, Folder 12 - those of Ephraim Williams and Elizabeth Jackson, and Oliver Partridge and Anna Williams.
  - Thomas Williams - Yale Diploma, 1741 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - William Williams - Notebook, 1693 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Birth Dates of Family Members, undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Inventory of Books and Prices, undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Weather Guide, undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Microfilm Guide
  The following outlines the sequence of items from this collection as they appear on the microfilm Williams, of Deerfield:
  Letters (#1 - #114) - These letters can be found in Box 1, Folders 1-3 and 5-8.
  Note Regarding Items in Map and Print Room (ca. pre-1972).
  3/24/1801 Tax Collection Instructions to Solomon Williams - Located within the collection in Box 2, Folder 4.
  Miscellaneous Items Sequenced #1-#56 - A wide variety of items with no particular order. Materials from inventories to poetry to medical recipes. Also, estate and legal papers and personal items. The items may be found in various folders throughout the collection.
  Notes/Bills (random arrangement) - Located within the collection in Box 1, Folders 13 and 14.
  Papers Related to Hinsdale Estate - Located within the collection in Box 1, Folder 17.
  " Military Papers #1 - #57 (random arrangement) - Located within the collection in Box 1, Folder 9.
  Military Papers #1 - #29 (random arrangement) - Located within the collection in Box 1, Folder 10.
  Letters from William Williams (#1 - #18) - The majority, those written to Thomas and Esther Williams, are located in Box 1, Folder 4.
  Capt. Oliver Shattucks Company Payroll Located within the collection in Box 1, Folder 11.
  Notebook of William Williams - Located within the collection in Box 2, Folder 11.
  9/18/1801 Tax Collection Instructions to Solomon Williams - Located within the collection in Box 2, Folder 4.
  Letters from Thomas Williams to Esther Williams (#1- #18) - Located within the collection in Box 1, Folder 5.
  Blotter - Call Phrase: BV Williams, Thomas Dr.
  Solomon Williams - Personal Account Book - Call Phrase: BV Williams, Solomon.
  Solomon Williams - Inhabitants of Deerfield Mass - Call Phrase: BV Williams, Solomon.